{
    "uid": "SOC-2090",
    "subject": "[Phish Report] Document Request - Review Org Chart",
    "reporter": "Alex Johnson",
    "instructions": "<p>The SOC received an alert about a quarantined email flagged by the company's email gateway solution. The email was sent to Alex Brown, a member of the operations team and appears to have been sent by the company's Human Resources SaaS solution, <i>HR Penguin</i>. </p><p>Using what you've learned within this domain, perform a detailed email analysis on the <code>challenge.eml</code> file to answer the investigative questions below.</p><h3>Challenge File:</h3><p><ul><li><code>~/Desktop/SOC_Level_1/Phishing_Analysis/Challenge/challenge.eml</code></li></ul></p>",
  
  
    "questions": [
        {
            "quid": "e992c68e",
            "question": "Based on the contents of the email header, what is the full <b>date and time</b> of the email delivery?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Check the contents of the <b>Date</b> header.",
            "placeholder": "***, ** *** **** **:**:** +****",
            "correct_answers": ["Tue, 14 Jan 2025 23:31:08 +0000", "Tue, 14 Jan 2025 23:31:08", "2025-01-14, 18:31"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "865f8b9e",
            "question": "What is the <b>subject</b> of the email?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Check the contents of the <b>Subject</b> header.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["Document Request - Review Org Chart"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "cc05b447",
            "question": "Who was the email <b>sent to</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Check the contents of the <b>To</b> header.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["alex@formbright.org"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "a833def4",
            "question": "Based on the sender's <b>display name</b>, who does the email claim to be from?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Check the contents of the <b>From</b> header. Specifically, the display name portion.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["Haley Smith"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "3bb52c59",
            "question": "What is the sender's <b>email address</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Check the contents of the <b>From</b> header. Specifically, the email address portion.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["hsmith@formbright.org", "<hsmith@formbright.org>"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "a0773db5",
            "question": "What email address will <b>replies</b> or <b>bounces</b> be sent to?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "This is also sometimes known as the bounce address or the reverse path. You can also check the Reply-To header for replies.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["hsmith@formbright.org.dilsrl.com", "<hsmith@formbright.org.dilsrl.com>"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "ed2f3b9d",
            "question": "What is email's <b>Message ID</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["<SA1PR14MB737384979FDD1178FD956584C1E32@SA1PR14MB7373.namprd14.prod.outlook.com>", "SA1PR14MB737384979FDD1178FD956584C1E32@SA1PR14MB7373.namprd14.prod.outlook.com"]  
        },
        {
          "quid": "89f330a6",
          "question": "What type of <b>encoding</b> was used to transfer the email body content?",
          "type": "text_input",
          "hint": "Look for any email headers related to content encoding.",
          "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
          "correct_answers": ["quoted-printable", "quoted printable"]  
      },
      {
          "quid": "2737434f",
          "question": "In <b>defanged</b> format, what is the URL extracted from the email?",
          "type": "text_input",
          "hint": "Use <a href=\"https://gchq.github.io/CyberChef/\" target=\"_blank\">CyberChef</a> to defang the URL. Make sure you also decode any content transfer encoding first!",
          "placeholder": "hxxp[://]*****************[.]***[.]**/",
          "correct_answers": ["http://dhnconstrucciones[.]com[.]ar/", "http://dhnconstrucciones[.]com[.]ar", "hxxp[://]dhnconstrucciones[.]com[.]ar/", "hxxp[://]dhnconstrucciones[.]com[.]ar"]  
      },
      {
        "quid": "b6bd1c80",
          "question": "Perform a <b>VirusTotal</b> lookup on the <b>URL</b> from the previous question. What verdict did <b>Fortinet</b> assign it?",
          "type": "text_input",
          "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
          "correct_answers": ["Malware", "Malicious"]  
      },
      {
        "quid": "7c363cd9",
        "question": "Run <code>emldump.py</code> against the email file. Which index number contains the file attachment?",
        "type": "text_input",
        "hint": "The script can be found under <code>Tools/emldump.py</code>.",
        "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
        "correct_answers": ["4"]  
    },

    {
        "quid": "3a95e5ad",
        "question": "What is the filename of the attachment?",
        "type": "text_input",
        "placeholder": "**_********-**.****",
        "correct_answers": ["HR_Orgchart-v2.docm", "(HR_Orgchart-v2.docm)"]  
    },

    {
        "quid": "ff1ea3e1",
        "question": "What is the <b>SHA-256</b> hash of the attachment?",
        "type": "text_input",
        "hint": "When using <code>emldump.py</code>, the <code>-s</code> option can be used to select a stream, <code>-d</code> can be used to dump the file, and <code>> FILENAME</code> can be used to redirect the output to a file.",
        "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
        "correct_answers": ["41c3dd4e9f794d53c212398891931760de469321e4c5d04be719d5485ed8f53e"]  
    },

    {
        "quid": "75477b08",
        "question": "Submit the hash value to <b>VirusTotal</b>. What is the <b>Popular threat label</b> returned for this sample?",
        "type": "text_input",
        "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
        "correct_answers": ["downloader.autdwnlrner/w97m"]  
    },
      {
        "quid": "e3157337",
          "question": "<b>[Yes or No]</b> - After your analysis, should the email be released to the user's inbox?",
          "type": "text_input",
          "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
          "correct_answers": ["no", "n"]  
      }
    ]
  }